The movie is set in a dystopian
future where technology has
become indispensable in performing
just about any task. At the start,
a man named Stripe dreams about a beautiful
woman. Soon, he wakes up and it is revealed
that Stripe is a new military recruit. He
is set to go on a mission with his squad,
which includes a female soldier named Hunter
Raiman and an arrogant soldier; Leonard.
Stripe’s team has been tasked with checking out
an infestation of “roaches” in a nearby village.
Roaches are pale, snarling, humanoid
monsters with sharp teeth. Apparently,
these creatures are vicious and they prey on
innocent people. It is Stripe's first field day
after his training so he is nervous and scared.
But when Raiman encourages him, he gets riled up.
Shortly after, the squad arrives at a
village, which has just been looted by a
bunch of roaches. The terrified villagers try
to explain the situation, but they speak in a
different language, which the soldiers can’t
comprehend. So, the group’s commander; Medina,
takes out a translator and starts interrogating
the villagers. She eventually learns that the
roaches escaped in the direction of someone named
Parn Heidekker. Parn is a solitary religious freak
who is apparently suffering from mental health
issues. The locals claim that he let roaches
cross his land and even left out food for them.
In the meantime, Stripe individually speaks
to the villagers and promises to one of them
that he will try his best to keep them safe.
Suspecting that Parn is helping the roaches,
the soldiers head out for his compound.
It is then revealed that each soldier
in the military has a neural implant called
MASS embedded in their brain which provides
data via AR or “Augmented Reality”. MASS also
helps the military in strategic operations.
Soon, the squad reaches Parn’s large compound
and plans their raid using holographic maps and
data displays, which each soldier has access to
thanks to the implants in their brains. Medina,
Stripe, Raiman and Leonard are in charge of
talking to Parn and searching the main house
while the others are assigned with
raiding the nearby outer buildings.
Executing their mission, Medina knocks on the
door and demands to inspect his home. A few
seconds later, a scared Parn answers and
it appears as if he is the only one home.
Although reluctant at first, he lets the soldiers
inside his house. Raiman and Stripe quickly go
about searching upstairs while Medina and Leonard
interrogate Parn. After talking to him for a bit,
Medina notices some religious symbols decorating
the walls. This makes her realize that Parn is
simply looking out for the roaches because
of some religious beliefs that all living
species must be protected. She attempts to
disabuse him of this notion by discussing the
supposed sickness in the roaches’ blood, which
doesn’t care about ideals of common humanity.
She also tells him that the roaches need to be
exterminated if humanity is going to survive.
Meanwhile, Stripe and Raiman search the room
upstairs to check for any roaches. They come
across a hidden room and decide to split up. In
one room, Stripe sees a blanket with multiple
shadows behind it. When he lifts the blanket,
he finds three terrifying roaches there. The
roaches appear to be pale humanoids with sharp
teeth, flattened noses and discolored eyes. One
of them holds up a mysterious device with a green
light. Stripe immediately shoots one in the head
and starts tussling with another. As the creature
attempts to bite him, he draws out his knife and
stabs the roach in the chest. Even after it is
dead, a disturbed Stripe continues stabbing it.
After the encounter, he examines the mysterious
green light device and experiences a flash
which causes a slight strain in his eyes. As
Raiman rushes to help him, she is knocked down
the stairs by an escaping roach. At the
same time, Parn attempts to stab Medina,
but he is easily subdued and taken into
custody. Before heading back to their base,
Medina decides to set the compound on fire, which
also destroys the mysterious green light device.
The next day, Raiman is seen practicing her
sharpshooting against roach targets, so that
none get away the next time. It is evident that
she is envious of a newbie like Stripe killing two
roaches on his first day. Soon, Stripe arrives
and joins in on the exercise. He aims at his
target but suddenly, his neural implant glitches
and he ends up missing. This worries Raiman but
Stripe insists that he is fine. However, during
push up exercises, his neural implant continues
to glitch which affects his performance. Medina
notices this and orders him to see a doctor.
Resolving to get to the bottom of the issue,
Stripe follows his commander's orders and goes
to the military hospital. The doctor runs
a diagnostic test on Stripe’s implant but
fails to find anything wrong. After a while,
Stripe tries to open up about the green device
which he found at Parn’s compound, but
the doctor doesn’t understand anything,
and simply refers him to a person called
Arquette. It turns out Arquette is a
resident military psychologist. He suspects
that Stripe's problem may have something to
do with the fact that he killed two roaches
brutally. He also claims that a few days of
proper rest should resolve everything. Before
parting ways, Arquette promises to get Stripe
an extremely good sleep by programming
something special for his dreams that night.
This dream involves the return of Stripe’s
recurring fantasy of the beautiful woman
surrounded by flowing drapes. This time,
though, it’s more intense. The lights are
red and she asks him to have coetus with
her. Stripe gives in and the two have a
wonderful time but just then, the glitch
turns up again, forcing him to wake up.
He sits up in his bunk and looks over his
comrades, who are all peacefully sleeping.
The next day, Stripe, Raiman and Medina are
back in the village helping out with food
and supplies. There, Medina informs the group
that a piece of information was extracted on
the roaches’ whereabouts from Parn. Hence, the
squad heads out to the said location to perform
a recon. After a while, the trio arrives at
an abandoned area and plans their recon with
the help of a drone and their MASS implants. As
the group continues discussing, Stripe's implant
glitches out again and malfunctions. Suddenly,
he realizes that he can smell the grass which he
could not before when the implant was working.
He tries to explain it to Raiman but she simply
ignores him. All of a sudden, shots are fired and
Medina is struck in the head, instantly killing
her. Despite the setback, Raiman somehow retrieves
the drone from the crossfire and uses it to locate
the shooter. It turns out that the roaches
are holed up in a room with a stolen rifle.
Stripe seems distraught but Raiman decides to make
their way into the compound providing cover fire
for each other. Stripe, who is still confused
and dizzy after the implant stopped working,
reluctantly agrees and follows his comrade.
There, the two find a kind of makeshift electronic
workshop, probably the source of that green-light
device from earlier. Shortly after, Stripe
finds something even more surprising. He
sees a normal-looking woman hiding out in one
of the rooms, begging for her life. She doesn’t
look like a roach, so Stripe tells her to get
out of there, promising not to hurt her. She
slowly backs into the hallway, attempting to
flee, but shockingly, Raiman shoots her dead.
This stuns Stripe and he questions why she killed
a civilian. But she simply brushes him aside and
moves forward, going on a killing spree, mowing
down all the roaches in the building. Strangely,
from Stripe's perspective, all the
roaches she kills look like normal humans,
which shocks him even more. Raiman then
proceeds to kill a frightened mother-son duo,
but before she can do so, Stripe intervenes
and knocks her unconscious. Sadly,
he also gets shot in the process. After a
while, he staggers to his feet and escapes
with the mother and son while profusely
bleeding. As Stripe leads them to safety,
Raiman wakes up and witnesses them getting
in the military vehicle and fleeing.
After having been shot in the belly and losing a
lot of blood, Stripe passes out behind the wheel,
making the car come to a complete stop in
the middle of the woods. Then, the woman
drags Stripe into her small hidden cave made up of
twigs and dirt and begins to treat his wound. He
soon regains consciousness and gets startled
by the woman applying bandages on his wound.
The woman introduces herself as Katarina and her
son as Alec. She then makes a major revelation.
It turns out that the Roaches the military has
been hunting are just normal beings. It is the
MASS implant that alters the soldiers’ senses,
and makes them look like inhumane monsters.
This is because the higher-class people look
upon the ‘roaches’ as some disease-ridden,
poor, and unintelligent beings. Katarina also
reveals that the green-light device used on
Stripe was built by her friend to mess with
the implants and make the soldiers see the
roaches as their real selves i.e., humans. The
roaches are victims of a genocide justified by
the military as genetic cleansing. A stunned
Stripe asks why the villagers hate the roaches,
despite them having no such implants.
Katarina responds that while the locals
see the roaches as humans, they still
treat them as inferior due to propaganda.
It turns out 10 years ago, the governments
ran DNA checks all around the world which
changed everything. People with genetic
predispositions to illnesses were categorized
as roaches which was a campaign set in
motion by television and internet media.
Unfortunately, as the two continue talking,
Raiman tracks them down. The two ‘roaches’
try running away, but they are immediately
shot and killed. This traumatizes Stripe and
he breathes heavily as Raiman walks
up to him while pointing her gun at
him. She then demands an explanation
for his earlier betrayal but Stripe,
who is still in a state of shock and
remorse, keeps murmuring to himself “None
of this is true ''. Sadly, this only puzzles
Raiman, and she knocks him out with her gun.
In the next scene, Stripe wakes up in a
white-walled cell crouching in the corner. Soon,
Arquette pays him a visit and offers him
coffee. He also apologizes to Stripe for
failing to catch the glitch in his neural implant
sooner. The psychologist then explains that the
green device he found in the farmhouse was
reverse engineered by the roaches from some
of the military’s drone parts. The light in
the device transmits a code which is like a
virus. It burrows into one’s MASS and tries to
shut it down from within. However, Stripes calls
everything a lie and insists that the roaches
look just like them. Arquette acknowledges it,
but also claims that the roaches are dangerous. He
then adds that humans are genuinely empathetic as
a species. And this is why creatures like
the roaches are taking advantage of them.
Following this, Arquette gives the example
of World War II during which most soldiers
didn’t fire their weapons or if they did, they
would just aim over the heads of their enemies
on purpose. In numbers, only 15 to 20% of the
soldiers would pull the trigger. The fate of the
world was at stake but only a small fraction of
them fired. Arquette comments that the war would
have gotten over a whole lot quicker had the
military grown some cojones and did their job.
Because of this, the officials had to figure
out a way to work around humans’ natural empathy
as many soldiers were afraid to kill. Arquette
reveals that MASS alters soldiers' senses such
as smell and sound so that they can kill without
hesitation or remorse. He then shows a video
evidence where Stripe consented to the memory and
sense altering effects of the Mass procedure. It
turns out that after Stripe was implanted with
the MASS, all his previous memories were erased.
Furious, Stripe attempts to attack Arquette,
but the latter uses the implant to blind him.
The cunning psychologist then offers him two
choices. Stripe can either allow the military
to reset his implant, wiping out his memory of
the past few days and this very conservation,
or to be incarcerated forever. Initially,
Stripe chooses to be incarcerated.
To help him reconsider, Arquette plays the
footage of the first mission in his mind. However,
in this footage, Stripe sees the real events
that unfolded without the alteration of the
MASS system. He witnesses himself brutally
murdering and stabbing normal people which
he then saw as roaches. He also learns that
the roach that had escaped from Stripe's first
mission was actually Katarina. As expected,
the footage breaks Stripe from the inside,
and he eventually decides to wipe
out his memory of the past few days.
In the final scene, Stripe, now a decorated
officer, leaves his base and approaches
a house. He has tears streaming down
his face as he smiles and watches the
girl from his dreams walk towards him
from the empty and dilapidated house.